Cheong Jia Wei Kenneth

| +65 9366 5477 | <u>clarinet.kenneth@gmail.com</u> | | linkedin.com/in/kenneth-cheong-jw | github.com/kenneth-cheong |

Professional Summary

Many years of experience in hospitality and service industry including sales. Making a midcareer switch to FinTech and open to options. Trained in Data Science and Analytics while taking Japanese for 6 years and Korean for 1 year respectively. Keen interest in process automation and business-driven analytics. High aptitude for learning, resourceful and efficient.

Core Competencies

- Coding: Python, SQL, HTML, CSS
- Software: PowerBI, MS Excel, Adobe Photoshop & XD, Final Cut Pro
- Languages: English, Chinese, Japanese, Korean
- Soft Skills: Communication, Customer Relations, Problem Solving, Stakeholder Management, Time Management

Work History

ACA Pacific Technology

Business Development Manager

Oct 2019 - Mar 2021

- Coordinated sales efforts for IoT, data science Platform, chatbots and other digitization solutions
- Managed vendors and system integrator partners
- Prepared and won tender bid for government educational institution for Al Marker & Tutor

Park Hotel Alexandra

Assistant Sales Manager

Feb 2018 - Mar 2019

- Negotiated favourable annual room rates for IT & Semiconductors
- Presented business case for hotel to 1 new company a week
- Crisis management for corporate clients using hotel services

F&B Executive Feb 2017 – Feb 2018

- Managed end-to-end enquiries to post-event evaluation for corporate meetings & social events
- Organised solemnization showcase events twice on hotel premises
- Exceeded social & corporate event sales annual budget
- Assisted in restaurant and banquet daily operations
- Conceptualized and executed décor for hotel events and promotions

Management Trainee

Aug 2015 – Feb 2017

- Rotated among various operations departments in the hotel (Housekeeping, Front Office, F&B)
- Achieved monthly target for Catering Sales when assuming Sales Manager position for 5 months

Singapore Airlines Limited

Flight Steward

Nov 2011 - Aug 2015

- Ensured adherence to safety onboard
- Provided world-renown excellent inflight service
- Prepared and served food and beverage in both Economy and Business Class
- Mentored junior crew to assist in their development

Education / Certification

SGUS Programme in International Financial Technology (FinTech)

National University of Singapore (2021)

- Blockchain, Algo-trading, Agile Project Management, Data Analytics (Power BI), Programming (Python, Javascript, MySQL)
- Final Project: Freelancer Platform using Blockchain. Co-Tech Lead focusing on UI/UX for website and video content

Data Science Immersive

General Assembly (2019)

- Machine Learning
- Python & SQL
- Web Scraping
- Final Project: Airlines Sentiment Analysis for United Airlines including categorization for managers to identify pain points of passengers and improve customer satisfaction. Done on large dataset of web scrapped tweets with ongoing automation to increase dataset size

Bachelor in Commerce (Hospitality & Tourism, Marketing)

Murdoch University (2013 - 2015)

Diploma (Hospitality and Tourism Management)

Temasek Polytechnic (2006 - 2009)

Japanese Language Proficiency Test N3

2018

WSQ Advanced Certificate in Training and Assessment (ACTA)

2013-2014

Hobbies

Drone Photography, Cycling, Badminton, Clarinet

References

- Andy Chua 9452 2688
 Direct Manager at Park Hotel Alexandra
- Sally Chen 8826 8831
 HR at ACA Pacific Technology